Guide to the Felix Bloch Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- PHYSICS DEPARTMENT, SERIES II
  - TRIBUTES TO COLLEAGUES
    This series contains alphabetically arranged files of notes, drafts, and manuscripts which Bloch saved from his preparation of tributes to William Fairbank, Werner Heisenberg, Hans Staub, Leonard Schiff, and David Locke Webster. Prepared for festschrifts, memorial services, the Academic Council, Physics Today, and the National Academy of Sciences' Biographical Memoirs, these tributes are records both of the lives of these famous scientists and of their influence on Felix Bloch. Bloch also wrote a biography of William Webster Hansen for the National Academy of Sciences, although none of the notes for this are in the collection.
    - William Fairbank Festschrift Speech, program, abstracts., (1982). (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Werner Heisenberg Festschrift Notes., (1960). (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Werner Heisenberg Festschrift. First draft. (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Werner Heisenberg Festschrift. Corrected draft. (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Werner Heisenberg Festschrift. Typed draft. (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Werner Heisenberg Festschrift. Correspondence, (1960-61). (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Werner Heisenberg Biography. Outgoing correspondence, (1976-77). (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Werner Heisenberg Biography. Incoming correspondence, (1977). (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Werner Heisenberg Festschrift. Requests for reprints, (1977). (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Werner Heisenberg Festschrift. Reprint of 1976 Physics Today article. (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Hans Staub obituary. Published in Physics Today. Correspondence & drafts, (1980). (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Leonard Schiff. Printed program for Memorial Service and Tributes, (1971). (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Leonard Schiff. Manuscripts of tributes. (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Leonard Schiff. Manuscript of Bloch tribute. (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Leonard Schiff. Establishment of lectureship. Correspondence, (1971). (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Leonard Schiff. Biographical notes, chronology. (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Leonard Schiff. Memorial Resolution for Academic Council. Correspondence & drafts, (1971). (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Leonard Schiff. Physics Today article Correspondence and drafts., (1971). (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Leonard Schiff. National Academy of Sciences biography. Correspondence, (1978-83). (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Leonard Schiff. NAS biography. First draft. (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Leonard Schiff. NAS biography. Corrected drafts. (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Leonard Schiff. NAS biography. Final draft. (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Leonard Schiff. NAS biography. Galley proof. (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - David Locke Webster obituary. Correspondence, (1976-77). (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - David Locke Webster obituary. Notes. (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - David Locke Webster obituary. Drafts. (Box 23, Folder 15)
- RESEARCH, SERIES III
  Series III contains research notes and notebooks, grant proposals and reports, contracts, patents, and apparatus designs. All the material contained in these boxes relates to Bloch's role as a research scientist.
  - NOTEBOOKS
    Bloch's bound notebooks are filed chronologically in this section. The notebook dated 1945-47 contains some of Bloch's calculations and notes on nuclear induction, the research for which he was awarded the Nobel Prize in Physics in 1952.
    Bloch's approach to physics is quite apparent in the pages of several of these notebooks. In them, he examines his ideas much as if he were a teacher explaining them to a student. He stresses clarity, brevity, and accuracy. More than once he comments on the relative elegance of his calculations. A researcher may find these pages a good source of information regarding Bloch's view and method of research.
    - 1941-48 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - 1945-47 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - 1952-57 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Undated (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - 1960 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - 1963-64 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - NOTES
    The notes contained in this section are filed alphabetically by subject. A few of the files contain correspondence and are so marked in the series inventory. Some notes relate specifically to work which Bloch later published; some are simply examinations of various topics. Dates included in the notes are given in the series inventory.
    - Atomic Accelerator proposal by Hofstadter. (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Atomic Research at Stanford. Speech. (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Attempt to observe electron deflection due to spin Density and fluctuations by photographic superposition Passage of protons through dees with upward harmonics Signals in oscillating field Simple echo theory, (1949), (1948), (1950), (1950), (undated). (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Behavior of a bose gas near the critical point. (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Bogolubov. (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Cooper pairs, (1962). (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Density fluctuations in a bose system. (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Depolarisation in nearly saturated fields. (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Effect of an exterior potential V(r). (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Effect of potential on a ring. (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Energy loss or gain by a fast-moving particle. (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Equilibrium and chemical potential. (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Fermi distribution with sound wave representation. (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Fetter's March 1969 paper on oscillator matrix. Correspondence and notes. (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Fetter manuscript on phonon scattering. (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Flux in thin cylinders, (1962). (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Flux quantization and dimensionality, (1967--). (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Flux quantization and dimensionality Notes continued., (1967--). (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Flux quantization and dimensionality Notes continued., (1967--). (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Flux quantization and dimensionality First draft of paper., (1967--). (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Flux quantization and dimensionality Second draft of paper., (1967--). (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - Flux quantization and dimensionality Third draft of paper., (1967--). (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - Flux quantization and dimensionality Manuscript and galley proof of paper., (1967--). (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - Flux quantization and dimensionality Drawings and figures for 'Flux quantization' and 'Josephson effect'., (1967--). (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - Form factors. (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - G-factor of the electron, (1953). (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - Heitler's theory of damping Line-narrowing by strong fields, (1964), (1956). (Box 25, Folder 27)
    - Heisenberg model for 2n spins, (1977). (Box 25, Folder 28)
    - Hellman-Feynman Theory. Notes. (Box 25, Folder 29)
    - Investigation of relaxation transition probabilities by double irradiation Nuclear moments experiment, (1958), (1949). (Box 25, Folder 30)
    - Josephson effect, (10/67-2/68). (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Josephson effect Notes, (10/67-2/68). (3-7/1968). (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Josephson effect Notes, (10/67-2/68). (6-7/1968). (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Josephson effect Notes, (10/67-2/68). (8/1968). (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Josephson effect Notes, (10/67-2/68). (4-9/1969). (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Josephson effect Miscellaneous notes., (10/67-2/68). (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Josephson effect Manuscript of paper., (10/67-2/68). (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Josephson effect Typescript of paper., (10/67-2/68). (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Kapitza effect, (1961). (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Landau's theory. (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Light scattering & density fluctuations in a Fermi gas, (1960). (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Light scattering & density fluctuations in a Fermi gas Notes continued., (1960). (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Low fluctuation expansion. (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous (untitled). (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Model for a discrete space-time, (1956-58). (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Noise. (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Order parameter in a Bose system, (1969). (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Phonon excitation. (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Photographic noise reduction. (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Quantized Hall effect. (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - Quantum effects in the partition function, (1963). (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - Quark experiment, oscillating force on a magnetically suspended sphere, (1971). (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - Rate equations for coupled systems. (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - Recent developments in nuclear induction. (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - Relaxation transitions with double irradiation, (1958-59). (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - Relaxation transitions with double irradiation Notes continued., (1958-59). (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - Rotating wall. (Box 26, Folder 27)
    - Some considerations regarding an accelerated superconductor, (1961). (Box 26, Folder 28)
    - Some remarks on Superconductivity, (1966). (Box 26, Folder 29)
    - Some remarks on Superconductivity Galley proof of paper, (1966). (Box 26, Folder 30)
    - Sound waves and incoherent light scattering in a Fermion system, (1961). (Box 26, Folder 31)
    - Stark ladders. (Box 26, Folder 32)
    - Stress tensor in -6 notation. (Box 26, Folder 33)
    - Stress tensor in -6 notation. Notes continued. (Box 26, Folder 34)
    - Superfluidity in a Ring Correspondence, drafts, manuscript., (1973). (Box 26, Folder 35)
    - Superfluidity in a Ring Drafts., (1973). (Box 26, Folder 36)
    - Superfluidity in a Ring Figures., (1973). (Box 26, Folder 37)
    - Torque upon a rotating superconductor in a magnetic field. First draft of paper. (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Torque upon a rotating superconductor in a magnetic field. Second draft of paper. (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Torque upon a rotating superconductor in a magnetic field. Third draft of paper. (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Track density. (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Trapping of flux by a Bose gas in a thin cylindrical ring Correspondence between Rorschach and Bloch, (1961). (1961-62). (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Trapping of flux by a Bose gas in a thin cylindrical ring Notes., (1961). (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Trapping of flux by a Bose gas in a thin cylindrical ring Notes., (1961). (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Trapping of flux by a Bose gas in a thin cylindrical ring First draft of paper., (1961). (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Trapping of flux by a Bose gas in a thin cylindrical ring Second draft of paper., (1961). (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Trapping of flux by a Bose gas in a thin cylindrical ring Draft of paper, part 1., (1961). (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Trapping of flux by a Bose gas in a thin cylindrical ring Draft of paper, part 2., (1961). (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Trapping of flux by a Bose gas in a thin cylindrical ring Draft of paper, part 3., (1961). (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Trapping of flux by a Bose gas in a thin cylindrical ring Draft of paper, part 4., (1961). (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Two-dimensional Tomanaga. (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Wentzel's superconductivity, (1958). (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Williams' cooperative paper. Notes. (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Williams' cooperative paper. Notes. (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Williams' cooperative paper. Draft of body of paper. (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - Williams' cooperative paper. Draft of appendies of paper. (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - Williams' cooperative paper. Corrected draft of paper. (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - Zero-sound and light scattering, (1960). (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - Zero-sound and light scattering Notes., (1960). (Box 27, Folder 22)
    - Dirac equation of an electron in a magnetic field. (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Dirac equation of an electron in a magnetic field. Correspondence, (1981). (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Dirac equation of an electron in a magnetic field. Notes. (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Dirac equation of an electron in a magnetic field. Notes. (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Dirac equation of an electron in a magnetic field. Notes. (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Dirac equation of an electron in a magnetic field. Drafts. (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Dirac equation of an electron in a magnetic field. Typescript report. (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Dirac equation of an electron in a magnetic field. Miscellaneous notes. (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Dirac equation of an electron in a magnetic field. Miscellaneous notes. (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - RESEARCH GRANTS
    This series contains primarily files relating to Bloch's research funded by the Office of Naval Research from 1946 through 1973. The number of people working under this contract, at times including as many as 5 professors and 14 research assistants, increased steadily until about 1964. Among the documents are periodic status reports specifying exactly who was working under the contract, what research they were doing, what equipment they were using, what results they had found, and any publications resulting from their research. This information could be particularly useful as a means of following the research interests of some of the members of the Stanford Physics Department (for example, Bloch, Walter Meyerhof, Willis Lamb, William Little) over an extended period.
    There are also two small folders containing Bloch's applications for Guggenheim and National Science Foundation grants. This infomation is apparently not complete. Although Bloch received several other fellowship, including a grant from the Rockefeller Foundation, before his journey to Stanford in 1934, there is no information directly pertaining to these contained in the collection.
    - Guggenheim Fellowship, (1958-59). (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - National Science Foundation, (1953). (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Office of Naval Research (ONR). Outgoing correspondence., December 1946-December 1950. (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - ONR. Outgoing., (January 1951-December 1964). (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - ONR. Outgoing, (January 1965-July 1969). (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - ONR. Outgoing, (February 1970-December 1973). (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - ONR. Outgoing, (February 1974-December 1974). (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - ONR. Incoming correspondence (Barkas). (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - ONR. Incoming (B) (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - ONR. Incoming (C-D). (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - ONR. Incoming (Edelsack). (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - ONR. Incoming (E-F). (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - ONR. Incoming (Glaser). (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - ONR. Incoming (G-H). (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - ONR. Incoming (K-L). (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - ONR. Incoming (Meyerhof, 10/54-10/56). (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - ONR. Incoming (Meyerhof, 1/57-12/59). (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - ONR. Incoming (Meyerhof, 3/60-11/62). (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - ONR. Incoming (Meyerhof, 2/63-1/66). (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - ONR. Incoming (Mulders). (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - ONR. Incoming (M-N). (Box 29, Folder 21)
    - ONR. Incoming (Padgett). (Box 29, Folder 22)
    - ONR. Incoming (P-S). (Box 29, Folder 23)
    - ONR. Incoming (T-W). (Box 29, Folder 24)
    - ONR. Contract proposals, (1955-62). (Box 29, Folder 25)
    - ONR. Contract proposals, (1965-69). (Box 29, Folder 26)
    - ONR. Contract proposals, (1970-73). (Box 29, Folder 27)
    - ONR. Contracts and travel requests. (Box 29, Folder 28)
    - ONR. Periodic Status Reports, (1946-47). (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - ONR. Periodic Status Reports, (1948-50). (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - ONR. Periodic Status Reports, (1951-53). (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - ONR. Periodic Status Reports, (1954-56). (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - ONR. Periodic Status Reports, (1957-59). (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - ONR. Periodic Status Reports, (1960-62). (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - ONR. Periodic Status Reports, (1963-65). (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - ONR. Periodic Status Reports, (1966-73). (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - ONR. Final Reports, (1946-54, 1955-64, 1964-74). (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - ONR. Final Progress Report on Nuclear Structure Group, (1964). (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - ONR. Reports on trips (Europe Australia, 1948 & 1950, 1974). (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - ONR. Drafts of reports and proposals. (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - ONR. Financial records. (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - ONR. Miscellaneous receipts. (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - CONSULTING AND LICENSE AGREEMENTS
    Included in this section are consulting contracts and equipment license agreements for, among others, Argonne National Laboratory and Varian Associates. There is a small amount of correspondence, but most of the folders contain only legal documents.
    - Argonne National Laboratory Contract, (1946-47). (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Carbide & Carbon Chemical Corporation Consulting Contracts, (1949-53). (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Monsanto Chemical Company Contracts, (1946-48). (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - United States Atomic Energy Commission. Consulting Agreements, (1946-49). (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Varian Associates License Agreements. Miscellaneous correspondence regarding License Agreements on US Patents #2561489 and #2960649. (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Varian Associates License Agreements. 'Method and Means for Chemical Analysis by Nuclear Induction', (October 1953). (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Varian Associates. Agreement for nuclear induction consulting and extension, (March 1954) (to September 1960). (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Varian Associates. License Agreement for 'Line-narrowing Gyromagnetic Apparatus', (July 1954). (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Varian Associates. License Agreement for 'Spin-spin Decoupling Gyromagnetic Apparatus' (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Varian Associates. License Agreement for 'Spinner Apparatus' on US Patent #3068399 and copy of patent., (July 1965) (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Varian Associates. License Agreement on 'Spin Decoupler', (July 1965). (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Varian Associates. Rubidium equipment agreement, (April 1967). (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - PATENTS
    Patents on Bloch's inventions included here come from the United States, Canada, France, Switzerland, and Great Britain. Primarily for gyromagnetic devices, these patents contain some detailed design specifications.
    - US #2960649 'Line-narrowing Gyromagnetic Device'. (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Sweden #166285. 'Line-narrowing Gyromagnetic Device'. (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Switzerland #336621. 'Line-narrowing Gyromagnetic Device'. (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - France #1126251. 'Line-narrowing Gyromagnetic Device'. (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Great Britain #789238 'Line-narrowing Gyromagnetic Device' and specification of patent. Great Britain #789100 'Gyromagnetic Resonance Method and Apparatus' and specification of patent. (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - US #23950 (originally #2561489). (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - Canada #645205 'High Resolution Gyromagnetic Resonance Spectrometer'. (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - APPARATUS DESIGNS
    Design plans and calculations for various pieces of research equipment, including magnets and an electron apparatus, are found in this section. Also included is correspondence regarding the transfer of Bloch's large magnet used for the first resonance measurements of organic molecules--the first high resolution nuclear magnetic spectroscopy--to the Smithsonian Institute's Museum of History and Technology.
    - Electron apparatus. Structural aspects, (1954). (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Electron apparatus. Structural aspects, (1954). (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Electrostatic well design and calculations. (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Magnet. Calibration curves. (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Magnet. Drawings and specifications. (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Graphs, drawings, calculations relating to misc. (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Smithsonian Institution. Correspondence regarding the transfer of Bloch's magnet to Washington, D.C., (1963-66). (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Smithsonian Institution. Annual Report of the Museum of History and Technology, picture of Bloch's magnet on page 260., (1967) (Box 32, Folder 8)
- ORGANIZATIONS, SERIES IV
  This series contains documents pertaining to Bloch's membership in and the administration of the many organizations, both personal and professional, with which he was affiliated. Correspondence within these files is either separated into outgoing and incoming letters or arranged chronologically depending on its extent and nature.
  Because of Bloch's scientific reputation, documented most visibly by his receipt of the Nobel Prize, many groups were anxious to have Bloch's name associated with their own. Often Bloch, stressing his other commitments, declined these invitations. Despite such time pressures, however, he found himself able to participate actively in several organizations. Among these were the American Physical Society, the International Society of Magnetic Resonance, and the Weizmann Institute of Science.
  The largest section in this series (6 boxes) is that of the American Physical Society, of which Bloch was president in 1965. Despite the size of these records, however, they cover thoroughly only the period of Bloch's presidency (January 1965-January 1966). From 1966 until 1971, he continued to serve on the Executive Council of the Society but these files are not complete.
  Included in this series is a file containing information regarding Citizens for Humphrey. The researcher should note, however, that Bloch was not actually a member of this organization. In fact, the file contains primarily letters exchanged by Bloch and various newspapers attempting to straighten out the erroneous inclusion of his name in a Citizens for Humphrey advertisement.
  - AMERICAN ACADEMY OF ARTS AND SCIENCES.
    - Correspondence, (1960-77). (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - AMERICAN ASSOCIATION FOR THE ADVANCEMENT OF SCIENCE.
    - Correspondence, (1965). (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - AMERICAN ASSOCIATION OF UNIVERSITY PROFESSORS
    - Correspondence, (1972). (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - AMERICAN FRIENDS OF THE WEIZMANN INSTITUTE OF SCIENCE (AFWIS).
    - AFWIS. Outgoing correspondence, (1954-83). (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - AFWIS. Incoming correspondence (A-C). (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - AFWIS. Incoming (D-H). (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - AFWIS. Incoming (L-P). (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - AFWIS. Incoming (R). (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - AFWIS. Incoming (S-W). (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - AFWIS. Incoming (Weiner). (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - AFWIS. Incoming (Weisgal). (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - AFWIS. Executive Council and Committee. (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - AFWIS. President's Report, (1978, 1982, 1983). (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - AFWIS. Minutes (miscellaneous). (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - AFWIS. Minutes (miscellaneous). (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - AFWIS. Proposed budget, (1982-83). (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - AFWIS. Proposed budget, (1982-83). (Box 33, Folder 17)
    - AFWIS. Obituary of Amos de Shalit. (Box 33, Folder 18)
    - AFWIS. Ion Accelerator and Accelerator Tower pamphlets. (Box 33, Folder 19)
    - AFWIS. Directory, (1982). (Box 33, Folder 20)
    - AFWIS. List of 25th Anniversary Sponsors. (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - AFWIS. Summary of News, (1982-83). (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - AFWIS. Science News and misc. publications. (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - AFWIS. The Weizmann Institute and Your Health. (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - AMERICAN FRIENDS OF THE HEBREW UNIVERSITY (AFHU)
    - AFHU. Outgoing correspondence, (1952-81). (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - AFHU. Incoming correspondence (C-H). (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - AFHU. Incoming (J-W). (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - AMERICAN INSTITUTE OF PHYSICS (AIP)
    - AIP. Outgoing correspondence, (1957-71). (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - AIP. Incoming correspondence (B-K). (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - AIP. Incoming (S-W). (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - AIP. Incoming (Williams). (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - AIP. Constitution. (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - AIP. Unpublished report: Report on pre-college physics study. (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - AIP. News release, (1964). (Box 34, Folder 14)
    - AIP. Newsletters, (1964-70). (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - AMERICAN PHILOSOPHICAL SOCIETY.
    - Correspondence, (1965-73). (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - BAY AREA COUNCIL ON SOVIET JEWRY.
    - Correspondence, (1975). (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - CAMBRIDGE PHILOSOPHICAL SOCIETY.